麦琪:嘿,你和迈克真的不留下来吃晚饭吗?
Maggie: Hey are you sure you and Mike can't stay for dinner?
我做了你爱吃的生菜.
I'm making a figment: Lettuce!
凯特:你太好了,西沃太太.不过,我和迈克买了票去看今晚的.
Kate: That's really sweet Mrs Siever but Mike and I have tickets to the Nut Cracker tonight.
麦琪:是芭蕾吗?迈克知道他们不卖花生,
Maggie: The Ballet?Does Mike know they don't sell peanuts and you can't
你不胡闹吗?
do the wave?
杰森:叮叮当,叮叮当,噢,
Jason: Jingle Bells Jingle Bells, ho ho ho.
噢,噢.猜一猜他们在圣诞树店里进了什么货?
Guess what they've got down at Mary's Trees Trees Trees.
麦琪:我要去买树吗?
Maggie: I have to go trees?
杰森:比任何树都要好.那些是12英尺高的尊贵的杉书,
Jason: They're better than any trees, these are twelve-foot noble firs,
只售8美元.
for only eight dollars.
麦琪:8美元?
Maggie: Eight dollars?
杰森:哦,是二手货.
Jason: Well, previously owned.
麦琪:杰森,我们今年不买大树了,
Maggie: Jason we are not gonna get a big tree this year because you know
因为你知道为了装饰你变成什么样了.
how you get when you decorate it.
杰森:很欢快?
Jason: Jolly?
麦琪:不,是杀气腾腾!
Maggie: Ho-ho-homicidal!Having everything your way!
独断专行!所以今年,我要尝试点新鲜的.
So this year we're gonna try something new.
杰森:麦琪,这不是圣诞树,是欧芹!
Jason: Maggie, that's not a tree, that's Parsley!
克莉丝:树小意味着礼物也小吗?
Chrissy: Does a little tree mean little presents?
麦琪:不,宝贝,你知道你多么关心保护地球吗?
Maggie: Ho sweetheart, you know how much you care about saving the Earth?
过完圣诞节后,我们可以把它种下去,也保护了它.
Well, after Christmas we can plant this tree and save it, too.
克莉丝:一年来,我都关心地球了.
Chrissy: All year long, I care about Earth.
在圣诞节,我关心的是我自己.
At Christmas, I care about numero uno!
迈克:好吧,凯特,你真想去看?
Mike: Ok, Katie, you ready to see the Nut Cracker?
杰森:迈克,你要去看芭蕾吗?
Jason: Mike, you're going to the Ballet?
迈克:是芭蕾吗?
Mike: It's a ballet?
开萝尔:是的,我很难过,
Carol: Yes, I am upset, and do you know why?
你知道为什么吗?德怀特霍利伯顿刚刚甩了我.
Dwight Halliburton has just stood me up!
开萝尔:我那么信赖他,现在我的心都碎成两瓣了.
Carol: I trusted him and now my heart is cleft in twain.
迈克:我希望你那两瓣心各奔东西,离的远远的.
Mike: Well I hope your twain will be leaving soon on a very long twip.
凯特:迈克,她这么伤心,你还在幸灾乐祸.
Kate: Mike, how could you do that to her when she is so upset?
迈克:哦,凯特,她总是这样的.她的名字都成了:开萝尔.
Mike: Oh, Kate, she's just always like that.
是的.我很难过.西沃.
It's just who she is: Carol-yes-I-am-upset-Siever!
凯特:哦,你不能去跟她谈谈吗?为了我,好吗?
Kate: Well, could not you go and talk to her?For me?
迈克:哦,好的.
Mike: Wa-el, okay.
杰森:噢,这孩子有人管着了.
Jason: Ouh, that boy is sm-itt-en!
麦琪:这孩子该遭罪了.
Maggie: That boy is wh-ipp-ed!
迈克:嘿,开萝尔,你干什么呢?
Mike: Hey Carol, what are you doing?
开萝尔:按字母顺序整理书架!我是想让你帮忙,
Carol: Alphabetizing the bookshelf!
可我没时间训练你.
I'd ask you for help but I'm too busy to train you.
迈克:我觉得你不想告诉我你那些愚蠢的事,是吗?
Mike: I realize you don't wanna tell me about your stupid problem right?
开萝尔:德怀特有了一个新的研究助手,叫费利西亚.
Carol: Dwight has a new research assistant named: Felicia.
迈克:我猜也是.
Mike: I guess you do.
开萝尔:今晚,我们本来要去看伊斯特万本德拉基的表演的.
Carol: And tonight we had tickets to see Istvam Penderecki.
迈克:谁是伊斯特万?
Mike: Istvam who?
开萝尔:他是个表演艺术家,一面向观众口吐污言秽语,
Carol: He's a performance artist who screams obscenities at the audience
一面在自己的头发上点火,这是他的圣诞专场.
while setting his hair on fire.That's his Christmas show
开萝尔:现在不重要了,因为他不去什么地方去,
Carol: Does not matter because he won't be going anywhere because I hate
因为我恨德怀特霍利伯顿,希望他一败涂地.和他去过的每个地方,
Dwight Halliburton before he even loses over!
开萝尔:德怀特宝贝,快回家,到妈妈这里来!对不起,先生!凯特,你的电话!
Carol: Dwight baby, come home to Mama!Sorry Sir!Kate, telephone!
凯特:谢谢.
Kate: Thanks.
迈克:开萝尔,你知道自己的问题是什么吗?
Mike: Carol you know what your problem is?
开萝尔:你和我是一个妈妈生的?
Carol: You and I both come from the same loin?
迈克:不,你身边的人让你嫉妒!
Mike: No, you get involved with people who make you jealous!
开萝尔:人人都嫉妒.
Carol: Everybody gets jealous.
迈克:我就不.因为我知道怎么挑选靠得住的女人,
Mike: Not me, because I know how to pick that woman I can count on,
你从没看到凯特甩我吧?
you don't see Kate standing me up do ya?
凯特:迈克?!!好消息!我相信…
Kate: Mike?!!Great news!I believe...
迈克:什么?
Mike: Huh?
凯特:是我的经纪人!我被选为泳装模特了.
Kate: It was my agent!I have been picked in the Sporting Man swimsuit edition.
下个星期,我们要到牙买加拍外景.
We shoot in Jamaica, next week.
所以,我立刻得去试服装.
So I have to get fitted for my suit right away.
迈克:可是凯特,啊,我多么盼望和你去看芭蕾啊.
Mike: But Kate, ah, I was so looking forward to going to the Ballet?
凯特:噢,(亲吻)我会补偿你的.
Kate: Oooh, (smooch) I'll make it up to you.
开萝尔:这是A,B…
Carol: It's A, B...
迈克:有两张的票,有谁感兴趣?
Mike: Anybody still interested in a couple of tickets to the Nut Cracker?
克莉丝:我去,我去!
Chrissy: I am I am!
迈克:好吧,50美元.
Mike: Ok, fifty bucks.
杰森:凯特怎么了?
Jason: What about Kate?
迈克:哦,她必须要走.
Mike: Oh she had to leave.
她的经纪人来电话了;她要为杂志拍泳装照片.
Her agent called; She got a job in the swimsuit edition of the Sporting Man.
本:就是那份让我疯狂的杂志吗?
Ben: The issue I live and die for?
卢克:姑娘就是喜欢穿性感的三点式.
Luke: Babes and postage stamp screen bikinis.
杰森:哦,小伙子们,去年,我就看过一期.哈哈,真的.克莉丝,你想跟老爸去看吗?
Jason: Boys, oh girl, I wanted to meet her last year, haha, I did.Chrissy
you wanna go to the Nut Cracker with your old man
克莉丝:好.
Chrissy: Yeah.
杰森:好吧.
Jason: Okay.
卢克:哦,凯特什么时候拍三点式?
Luke: So, uh, when is Kate doing this bikini shoot?
迈克:下周在牙买加.
Mike: That' s next week in Jamaica.
本:哦,我喜欢当那个摄影师.
Ben: Oh, I love to be the photographer on that job.
一个男人,其他都是漂亮姑娘.
I mean one guy all those babes?
卢克:哦,算了吧!我愿意是那个往姑娘们身上涂油的人.
Luke: Well, um, forget that!I'd love to be the guy who rubs on the
coco butter
本:算了吧,我愿意是她们身上的油.
Ben: Forget that, I'd love to be the coco butter!
迈克:嘿,你们为什么不去滚雪球?这只是很普通的拍照而已.
Mike: Hey, why do not you guys run a roll in the snow?Well, that's no ordinary photo shoot.
本:是的,也许,但如果凯特是我的女朋友,我不会让她去牙买加的.
Ben: Yeah, maybe, but if Kate was my girlfriend I sure would not let her go to Jamaica.
麦琪:本,你哥哥相信凯特.
Maggie: Ben, your brother trusts Kate.
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah!
麦琪:我真为你俩害臊.凯特是专业模特.
Maggie: I am appalled of you two.Kate's a professional.
她能浑身涂着油,穿着三点式,
Now she can stand in the sun all oiled up in the briefest of bikinis,
站在阳光下,
having her picture taken by some jet-set photographer without anything
让那些阔佬摄影师为她拍照,而绝不发生任何麻烦事.
untoward
高兴的是,至少迈克知道这一点.
happening.I am glad that at least Mike knows that.
弗兰西斯:我17岁的时候,那一年真是好…你来这里做什么?
Francis: When I was seventeen, it was a very good year....What are you doing here?
迈克:你叫我来的啊.
Mike: You sent for me.
弗兰西斯:啊,明白了.
Francis: Ah, I understand you volunteered to drive the bus for this year's
你是不是自愿开车送孩子们去参加今年砍伐圣诞树的活动?
Christmas tree cutting trip?
迈克:是的.我觉得对那些生活在城市里的孩子们来说,
Mike: Yeah, I thought it might be a nice chance for some inner city kid
这是一个很好的机会去体验圣诞节.那里有白雪,银铃和野生植物.
to experience Christmas.You know the snow, the silver bells, the mistletoe.
弗兰西斯:算了吧.这个活动有点危险.
Francis: Forget that.Think Nunez with a Chainsaw!
西沃,你自己领他们去是没这个资格的.
Siever, you don't have the seniority to do this on your own.
如果你坚持带他们去的话,我只能跟你一起去了.
If you insist on taking them on this trip, I'll be forced to go ith you.
迈克:太好了,人越多,气氛越浓.
Mike: Great, the more the merrier.
弗兰西斯:西沃,我哪里得罪你了?
Francis: Siever, have I ever done you any harm?
迈克:哦,泰德斯科先生,怎么说呢,这周,我需要找点事做.我女朋友去外地了.她是一个模特,
Mike: Look, Mr.Tedesco, I'll level with ya, I need to find something to do
this week while my girlfriend is outta town, see she is a model
她要去牙买加为杂志拍什么泳装照片.
and she is gonna be in Jamaica doing the swimsuit issue of the Sporting Man.
弗兰西斯:哦,
Francis: See, let me give some unsolicited advice:
我主动给你提个建议吧:搭下个航班去牙买加.
Catch the next thing smoking to Jamaica.
迈克:哦,泰德斯科先生,我和凯特彼此信任.明白吗?我们是相爱的!
Mike: Well, Mr.Tedesco, Kate and I trust each other okay?We're in love!
弗兰西斯:你不知道爱情是疯狂的吗??我娶泰德斯科太太是因为她有一个高挑,
Francis: Don't you know love is a state of insanity??
苗条的身材;
I myself married Mrs Tedesco because she had a body that would not stop.
可嫁给我后,她就开始发福了.
Shortly after I married her, it stopped.....Love!...
爱情!只能让你失去判断力.
Makes your judgement take a holiday.
你还以为自己娶了一个天使呢,
You, you think you are marrying a goddess;
结果却发现她是个穿着浴衣读无聊小报的粗俗女人.
And you wind up with a walking bathrobe that reads the Tinsel town Tattler!
迈克:哦,泰德斯科先生,我确信自己了解凯特…非常了解.
Mike: Look, Mr.Tedesco.I am darn sure that I know Kate... pretty well.
弗兰西斯:但你知道奈杰出尔多恩吗?
Francis: But do you know Nigel Done.
迈克:不,他是谁啊?
Mike: No.Who is he?
弗兰西斯:他是的首席摄影师.
Francis: He is the chief photographer for the Sporting Man.
他是一个澳大利亚人,粗壮而英俊,
He is an Australian with rugged good looks and an appetite for every lovely
喜欢追逐…他拍照的每个可爱的模特.
model he photographs.
迈克:你怎么知道这些的?
Mike: How do you know all this?
弗兰西斯:从小报上看的."浴室是一个好地方…"
Francis: I read in the Tattler."The bathroom can be lonely place..."
杰森:好了,儿子.现在看起来怎么样?
Jason: Okay son.How does it look now?
本:好极了.
Ben: Perfect.
杰森:呵呵呵,啊,看,
Jason: Hehehe, aw, come on Ben, it's still crooked!
本,还是有点歪!至少偏了2度呢!
That's at least two degrees off!
本:我看很直啊.
Ben: Looks straight to me.
杰森:我们要高标准地做好…
Jason: Pretty straight does feed the ring here pal...
麦琪:怎么样了,你们?
Maggie: How's it going guys?
杰森:嘿,棒极了,充满了圣诞的气氛.
Jason: Hey great, just full of Christmas spirit.
本:至少有气氛,那就好.
Ben: At least it's full of it all right.
麦琪:哦,杰森,你又得意忘形了?
Maggie: Oh, Jason are you starting it again?
本:是的,不过,你怎么总是这么认真呢?
Ben: Yeah, but how do you always take this so seriously?
卢克:是的,圣诞节应该是快乐的.
Luke: Yeah, Christmas is supposed to be fun.
杰森:卢克,快乐不是天上掉下来的.快乐是精心准备得来的.
Jason: Luke, Fun does not just happen.Fun is a matter of exacting preparation.
所有人:哦,不.
All: Oh no.
杰森:是的,不过,圣诞节一年一度,必须事事完美.
Jason: Yeah but, Christmas is the one time that you want everything to be right.
因为我知道当这些装礼物的袜子挂成42度角,花环在门的正中间时,
Cuz I know when those stocking are hung at a 42-degree angle and that
我们才能获得节日的快乐.
reed's centered precisely on the door is gonna fill us all with utile joy.
杰森:而且,一个随随便便的圣诞节不过是…
Jason: Besides, a sloppy Christmas is nothing more than a ..
所有人:一个破乱节日.
All: Groundhog Day with Denzel.
克莉丝:爸爸,放松点.
Chrissy: daddy, loosen up.
杰森:我很放松,宝贝,
Jason: I am lose sweetheart, I just have a crooked tree,
我只是把树放歪了,我一定要安排好.
something's just out of whack here.Uh, I must have the screw loose.
迈克:哦,撒谎的凯特…爸爸关于"破乱节日"的演说开始了吗?
Mike: Ooh, lying sonnets... Is it time for dad's Groundhog with Denzel speech?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yea it is.
迈克:(吸气)啊.
Mike: (snaps) Ah.
开萝尔:如果有人问就说我去图书馆了.
Carol: If anyone asked I am off to the library to get a good look at
我要好好看看德怀特那个轻佻的研究助手费利西亚.
Dwight's hussy new research assistant Felicia.
迈克:哦,开萝尔,
Mike: Aw, Carol, you're gonna spy on somebody outta jealousy?
你以为嫉妒就去监视别人吗?这太幼稚了,只有可怜的傻瓜才干这个.
It's completely infantile.Only pathetic fools do that.
开萝尔:你想去吗?
Carol: So you wanna come?
迈克:好吧,好吧,去看看,好好侦察一下她.不过我要说清楚,只要是个会喘气的女人,她就比你强.
Mike: Alright alright, go check out, check out the invitation, but let me be clear
if she is female, breathing, she is 2 of you
杰森:为什么这么打击她呢,你没看她很痛苦了吗?
Jason: Why do you need her like that, can't you see she is in pain?
迈克:算了吧,爸爸,她会嫉妒德怀特吗?那个书虫?谁会看上他呢?
Mike: Come on dad, she is jealous over Dwight??Duke of Dork?Who's gonna be around him?
杰森:费利西亚就会?!!如果两个人一起亲密地工作,很自然他们就会互相吸引.
Jason: Felicia might?!!It's only natural, when people work closely together, they become attracted to each other.
对吗?研究员和学者,演员和导演.
Right?Researchers and scholars, actors, directors.
迈克:模特和摄影师?
Mike: Models and photographers?
杰森:绝对!这正是我担心的,呃,这是一个例外.
Jason: Exactly!That, that's the hole in my fear, that's eh, the exception.
凯特:啊,真令人兴奋.
Kate: Ah, isn't this exciting?
迈克:是的,我是第一次!现在可以回家了吗?
Mike: Yeah, my first press party!Can I go home now?
迈克:呵呵!看她们穿的什么啊.你觉得有人真的会出钱给那些女孩吗?
Mike: Hehehe!Look at the lines in those pants, you think somebody might actually pay
money for those babies
陌生人:特威德夹克?你相信他真的会付钱吗?
Stranger: Tweed jacket?Can you believe he actually paid money for that?
奈杰尔:你在这里,凯特,亲爱的!
Nigel: There you are, Kate, darling!
迈克:亲爱的?
Mike: Darling?
凯特:在这样的晚会,人们都这样称呼.
Kate: It's the way people talk at these parties.
凯特:奈杰尔多恩,这是迈克西沃.
Kate: Nigel Done, this is Mike Siever.
奈杰尔:你好,达尔文?呵呵.
Mike: Hello, Darwin?hehehe.
奈杰尔:你穿上了肯定美艳照人.你觉得呢?
Nigel: You are going to look fantastic in this Suit: What do you think?
迈克:凯特?你…
Mike: Kate?Euh...
凯特:迈克?所有模特实际上都穿这样的衣服.
Kate: Mike?All the models are actually wearing suits like these.
迈克:哦,其他模特要跳楼,你也跳吗?
Mike: Well, other models are jumping off the building, would you do that too?
奈杰尔:不理他,宝贝,我把你介绍给记者们.
Nigel: Come on angel, let me introduce you to the press.
对不起,迈克,男友禁止.
Sorry Mike no boyfriends allowed.
奈杰尔:(摆姿势并喃喃说话)宝贝…呜,宝贝.
Nigel: (posing and mumbling) Baby...Hm.Baby.
杰森:嘿,我准备好了.我找到了垂直线,我情绪高涨,我还需要一个帮手把圣诞树摆放垂直了.
Jason: Hey, I am ready with my square, I get my plumb line, I get my spirit level, I could use a little help getting the tree straight.
麦琪:我要去擦洗马桶.
Maggie: I have to go scrub the toilets.
本:我要去写科学报告.
Ben: I have to get a credit for the science report.
卢克:我要去擦手写板.
Luke: I have to get the script off the whiteboard.
克莉丝:我要去喝菠菜汤.
Chrissy: I gotta eat some spinach.
杰森:那好吧,我一个人享受乐趣.哦,你看来准备好帮我摆放圣诞树了.凯特飞黄腾达了,是吗?
Jason: Ok then, that's all the more fun for me!Mike, oh, you look like
you're ready to go beg some trees.Kate's flagging up ok
迈克:是的,是,一切都很好,爸爸.
Mike: Yeah, yeah, it was fine dad.
杰森:你还好吧?你有什么心事?
Jason: Are you alright?Something on your mind?
迈克:哦,实际上,是的.
Mike: Oh, well actually yeah.
杰森:哦,别动,我最后放!呃,我去拿扫帚,只许看,别动.别向我诉苦.
Jason: Oh!Hang on, that order is my last!Uh, I gotta get a broom
just look but don't touch.Don't start with me
迈克:听着,开萝尔,我错了.
Mike: listen Carol, I was wrong.
开萝尔:为什么你只有在没人的时候才说呢?
Carol: Why you only do this when they're no witnesses?
迈克:不,
Mike: No no I mean it.
不,我是认真的.
And you have every right in the world to be jealous of Dwight and his
你完全有理由去嫉妒德怀特和他的助手费利西亚.
assistant Felicia.
开萝尔:今天下午我看到德怀特的助手了,她是个比我老的女人.
Carol: I saw Dwight's assistant this afternoon.She's an older woman.
迈克:啊,真遗憾.
Mike: Aw, I am sorry.
开萝尔:不,我是说老…兰色的头发,黑色眼镜,看电影付半价.
Carol: No, no, I mean ooold, blue hair, black glasses, get sent movies with half the price.
迈克:哦,很明显如果她年轻,漂亮的话,就要有事发生了.
Mike: Oh, obviously something could have happened if she was young and attractive.
热情奔放,乌烟瘴气,珠光宝气,歌舞升平,锣鼓喧天.
With all that heat, and the dust, and the glitter, and the glamour and the parties and steel drums pounding?
开萝尔:在图书馆?
Carol: In the library?
迈克:哦,是图书馆还是牙买加并不重要.
Mike: Oh whether it's the library or Jamaica does not matter.
开萝尔:等等,你在说凯特吗?
Carol: Wait a minute, you are talking about Kate?
迈克:嘿,嘿,嘿,别提凯特和奈杰尔多恩.
Mike: Hey hey hey, You leave Kate and Nigel Done out of this.
开萝尔:奈杰尔多恩?太好了.
Carol: Nigel Done?This is wonderful.
我什么都不嫉妒,是你在嫉妒奈杰尔,那个澳大利亚大众情人?
I was always jealous about nothing, and you are
jealous about Nigel-tiny-Kangaroo-dance- ur, Done
弗兰西斯:我们走吧,西沃.你组织了一大帮拿着电锯的孩子.你要是不快点,我们可不好交差了.
Francis: Let's go Siever.You are hustling some kids with chainsaws out there.If you don't hurry, we'll be driving convertibles.
迈克:泰德斯科先生,我不去了.
Mike: Mr.Tedesco, I can't go.
弗兰西斯:这的音响绝对可怕!刚才,我好像听你说"我不去了".
Francis: Your cook stinks in here, absolutely horrid!For a moment out there it sounded as if you said, "I can't go."
迈克:不去了.
Mike: I can't.
弗兰西斯:不!
Francis: Nnnno!
迈克:泰德斯科先生,我要去牙买加.
Mike: Mr.Tedesco, I have gotta go to Jamaica instead.
弗兰西斯:什么??
Francis: What??
迈克:就是你告诉我要把凯特盯紧的.
Mike: Look, you're the one who told me to keep tabs on Kate.
弗兰西斯:你不能这样对我,退休以前我需要这份工作.
Francis: You can't do this to me.I need this job till retirement.
我有老婆,这笔退休金是我唯一的指望,
I have a wife and this pension is really the only thing we have going.
我知道孩子们不懂得这个,但我们已经决定了,我…
I know it's no substitute for Children but we made a decision, I...
迈克:泰德斯科先生,我不能退缩,我必须得去牙买加.
Mike: Mr.Tedesco, I did not quit.Look, I have gotta go to Jamaica.
弗兰西斯:哦,好吧,如果你执意要去,帮我一个忙.
Francis: Ohhhh.Well, if you must go, do me one favour:
迈克:什么?
Mike: What's that?
弗兰西斯:带上我!
Francis: Take me with you!
迈克:我为什么来到牙买加呢?我相信一切都好.
Mike: Why am I in Jamaica? I'm sure everything is fine.
奈杰尔:好,把它给我,宝贝.就这样,
Nigel: Okay give it to me baby.That's it, beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.
太美了,太美了,太美了.好,向我这转一点.
Okay turn a little more towards me.
我喜欢.太好了,就这样,是的,就这样!
I love it.I love it.Great.It's happening.Yes, it is.!
迈克:凯特!
Mike: Kate!
奈杰尔:太美了,很好,现在站起来,就这样.对,太美了,太美了.对,就这样.让我看看后背.
Nigel: Beautiful, alright stand up now.That's it, that's it, okay.Beautiful, beautiful.Yes, it's working.Let me see the back?
好的,我想你需要…
Okay, I think what you need is ...
迈克:别碰她.别碰她!
Mike: Don't touch her.Don't you touch her!
迈克:该死!你碰她了!
Mike: Dah!You touched her!
奈杰尔:好,你是谁的男朋友?
Nigel: Okay, whose boyfriend are you?
迈克:凯特的!
Mike: Kate's!
奈杰尔:姓什么,请问!
Nigel: Last name, please!
迈克:凯特麦克唐纳!就是她!
Mike: Kate McDonald!Her!You are Kate?
你不是凯特?不过没关心,我保护所有的女性!
But that's okay, I was defending all women!Everywhere!
世界各地的!我相信她会感谢我…
And I am sure she's grateful...
奈杰尔:你的凯特没戏了.
Nigel: your Kate's off the shift.
迈克:不,不,不,你不能这么做!
Mike: No, no no, you can't do that!
奈杰尔:我已经做了!
Nigel: Already done!
迈克:好吧,假如我道歉并让你再打我呢?
Mike: Well, what if I apologize and let you hit me again?
奈杰尔:这很诱人,不过谢谢了.凯特在那个小屋里养伤呢.
Nigel: it's tempting but no thanks.Kate's up the Boot Shacks recovering.
迈克:养伤?
Mike: Recovering?
凯特:迈克!
Kate: Mike!
迈克:凯特!
Mike: Kate!
凯特:你怎么到这来了?
Kate: What are you doing here?
迈克:你的腿怎么了?
Mike: What happened to your leg?
凯特:哦,我让水母叮了一下!你的眼睛怎么了?
Kate: Oh, I got stung by a jellyfish!What happened to your eye?
迈克:我,我,没有把带伸缩架的桌子放好,碰的.
Mike: I, I, forgot to put up my tray table in the upright position.
凯特:你都想不到奈杰尔是什么样的人.我一上飞机,
Kate: You won't believe what Nigel did.
他就想跟我调情.
The minute I got on a plane he made a pass at me.
迈克:我早知道,那个卑鄙的家伙就想跟你调情.没发生什么,是吗?
Mike: I knew it, I knew it, that scumbag just made a pass at you.Nothing happened right?
凯特:是的.
Kate: Nothing.
迈克:我早知道!
Mike: I knew it!
我的女朋友是世界上最好的女孩,
I have got the most wonderful girl in the world and nothing could come
我们的关系是牢不可破的.
between us!
模特:奈杰尔让我来看看你怎么样了.
Model: Nigel sent me over to check if you're all right.
迈克:哦,她很好.
Mike: Yeah, she's all right.
模特:不是她.是你,
Model: Not her, golden gloves, you!
拳王!我们没有药给你敷,但我拿来了一条冻河豚.
We don't a stick to put on that but I'll send over for chilled blow-fish.
听我说,
Listen, don't feel bad,
别难过了.你不是地一个因嫉恨而袭击奈杰尔的男朋友.
you're not the first jealous boyfriend who attacked Nigel.
所以他现在是一个拳击高手.
That's why he got his black belt.
凯特:你袭击了奈杰尔?这段时间我一直以为你放心我.
Kate: You attacked Nigel?This whole time I thought you were handling things.
可你并不相信我.
You just did not trust me.
迈克:凯特,我这样做是为了你.我了解奈杰尔这种人!
Mike: Kate, look I did it for you, I know guys like Nigel.
凯特:你更应该了解我.
Kate: And you know me better.
迈克,
Mike, I am not the kinda girl who is gonna get involved with sly guys
我不是那种跟奈杰尔这样花花肠子的男人鬼魂的女孩.
like Nigel Done!
迈克:可是我…
Mike: But Kate.
凯特:再见,迈克.
Kate: Goodbye Mike.
杰森:哦,圣诞树,哦,圣诞树,你高高地挺立…哦,你一点都不歪,笔直笔直的!哦,圣诞树,
Jason: Oh Christmas tree,  o Christmas tree  you are standing perpendicularly...Oh you are not
one or two degree not most upright!O Christmas tree
哦圣诞树,哦,圣诞书.我要让他们整个夜晚疯狂起来.
Oh Christmas tree, O Christmas tree we'll show them all night crazy!
好吧,各位,该装饰圣诞树了!
All right time to decorate the tree everybody!
好像我是唯一有圣诞节气氛的人.
Seems I am the only one with the Christmas spirit.
麦琪:别吃手指.
Maggie: Don't eat your fingers.
卢克:每个人都在笑,在装饰圣诞树,
Luke: Everybody laughing, making decorations,
我想像中的圣诞节就是这个样子.
now this is how I always imagined Christmas would be.
克莉丝:踏-哒!
Chrissy: Ta-da!
麦琪:哦,太好了!多漂亮的飞机啊,放到圣诞树上.
Maggie: Oh, this is great!Nice plane, let's put it on the tree.
大家:噢…
All: Ooooh.
麦琪:真是一棵完美的圣诞树…
Maggie: That's the perfect tree.....
开萝尔:你去哪了?
Carol: Where have you been?
迈克:哦,我花光了钱飞了600英里去牙买加,去让女朋友把我给甩了,还把眼睛给伤着了.
Mike: Well, I just spent my last dime to fly over 600 miles to Jamaica, to get dumped by my girlfriend, get punched in the eye.
开萝尔:旅行社太糟糕了.
Carol: How lousy a travel agent.
迈克:开萝尔,你是对的.我犯了嫉妒病.
Mike: Carol, you were right, I was jealous.
开萝尔:不,你是对的,我也是.
Carol: No, you were right, I was jealous.
迈克:你也是?我听你说费利西亚是个老女人.
Mike: Of what?I thought Felicia was probably good material.
开萝尔:我看到的是爱舍尔.费利西亚是个22岁的,
Carol: It was Esther I saw.Felicia is 22.
像米歇尔费沃一样漂亮的女孩.
Kind of a good-looking Michelle Fiver.
迈克:提前给你的圣诞礼物:我和凯特黄了!
Mike: Probably give a Christmas present early: Kate and I broke up!
开萝尔:我和德怀特也一样!
Carol: Dwight and I did too!
迈克:真的?呵呵!爱情太讨厌.
Mike: Really?Heh!Love stinks.
开萝尔:是的,可恶.
Carol: Yeah, Pee you!
迈克:是,只有家好.
Mike: Yeah, family's all you got.
开萝尔:说对了.我们相亲相爱,谁还需要德怀特和凯特啊?
Carol: You bet.Who needs Dwight and Kate when we have each other?
迈克:说的太好了,我们一起出去!
Mike: Now you're talking, let's hang out together!
开萝尔:对!我们去博物馆,去听歌剧,哇!
Carol: Yeah!We'll go to museums, to operas, whoo!
我们一起住一间房子,我们养猫,养很多的猫!
We'll get a house together, and we'll get cats, lotsa cats!
迈克:好啊,先休息下,我们去看电影?
Mike: Alright, let's stop and see a movie?
开萝尔:好啊,我去拿报纸.
Carol: Okay, I'll get the paper.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
凯特:为什么…
Kate: Why...
迈克:你知道,凯特,我也在问自己同样的问题.为什么我成了一个麻木的,嫉妒成性的傻瓜?
Mike: You know Kate, I was asking myself the same question, why I was an insensitive jealous fool?
凯特:不,我为什么对你发火?
Kate: Nooo, why can't I stay mad at you?
迈克:噢,你是个多好的女孩啊!
Mike: Uh, what a girl I've got!
迈克:从现在开始,我永远信赖你.
Mike: From now on, I am gonna trust you at all times!
开萝尔:好了,迈克,我找到电影预告了.
Carol: Ok, Mike, I got the Movie Guy.
迈克:哦,走开,猫小姐.
Mike: Oh beat it, Cat Lady.
开萝尔:什么!??我以为你俩黄了呢.
Carol: What!??I thought you two were on the rocks.
迈克:开萝尔,我们像是黄了吗?
Mike: Carol, does this look like we are on the rocks?
凯特:哦,这是给你的??我在外边发现的,这是给开萝尔的!
Kate: Oh, those are for you??I found them outside, they were for Carol!
开萝尔:给我,
Carol: Give me those you Tree Stumb.
你这木头.听一听:"玫瑰红,
Listen to this: "Roses are red Violets are blue I fired Felicia,
紫罗兰蓝 我炒了费利西亚 因为我爱你!"
Because I love you!"
签字:德怀特霍利伯顿,你中世纪的王子.
Signed: Dwight Halliburton, your medieval prince.
开萝尔:啊!这真是他送来的?
Carol: Huh!Does not he just send you?
迈克:对啊.就放在这里.
Mike: Yeah, right into the parcel of Brawn.
杰森:你们大家能不能到客厅里一下?
Jason: You guys wanna come in to the living room for a bit?
迈克:哦,圣诞树一定准备好了?装着你喜欢.
Mike: Oh the tree must be ready?Pretend that you like it.
杰森:过来,来吧,闭上眼睛!
Jason: Come on come.Cover your eyes!
迈克:好的,闭上眼睛.
Mike: Okay, cover your eyes.
杰森:来吧,嘘!别吵醒了小精灵们.噢.
Jason: Come on, Shhh!Don't wake the elves.Oops.
克莉丝:能看看我们的礼物吗?
Chrissy: Can we look at our gifts?
杰森:不,不,还不行.我要给你们一个惊喜,
Jason: No, no, nobody look, I want it to be a surprise, alright,
好了,都准备好了吗?芝麻开门.
everybody ready?Open Sesame.
麦琪:怎么回事,你还没弄完吗?
Maggie: What's the matter you did not finish?
本:也许他在等从北极来的设计蓝图呢,
Ben: it's probably waiting for the blueprints to get back from the North Pole.
杰森:不,我弄完了,我想剩下的工作你们大概愿意自己动手.
Jason: No, I am done, I just thought the rest of you might finish it up without me.
卢克:你是说我们想怎么装饰就怎么弄吗?
Luke: You mean we could decorate your tree any way we want?
杰森:是的,这不是我的圣诞树,是我们的圣诞树.有时你们难以相信,但我把它交给你们了.
Jason: Yes, look, its not my tree, it's our tree.I know it is hard to believe sometimes I just get carried away.
麦琪:哦,杰森.
Maggie: Oh, Jason.
本:那我们可以大把地往树上挂彩带了.
Ben: So can we put tinsel on in big handfuls?
杰森:你愿意就好.
Jason: If you wish?
克莉丝:我想把糖果放在哪儿就放到哪里吗?
Chrissy: I can put the candy kings in any crazy place we want?
杰森:你高兴就好.
Jason: If the spirit moves you?
卢克:把重的东西放在树梢上可以吗?
Luke: And I put the heavy ornaments on top?
杰森:不,不,不能.
Jason: No, no, no.
麦琪:哦,不!
Maggie: Ah, no!
杰森:好吧,可以!不过…
麦琪:噢!就是这样.
00:21:55,800
Jason: Yeah, alright!But... Maggie: Yeah!That's right.